Gu-cheon!
Please come to your senses.
Are you all right?
Gu-cheon.
THE EAST PALACE
So you drove out 13 court ladies' spirits
in the salt storehouse?
You have done well.
You may withdraw.
I have something to ask you.
Did you have anything to do
with the broken seal
on the salt storehouse?
You have changed.
to dare ask such a thing now.
But as a child.
you must have seen how such words
led to bloodshed upon the palace.
You saw what befell your mother.
"I will wipe out every last seed
of the East Palace."
The Most Favored Lady of the Court
who died in the pond said this.
She is the pond spirit. is she not?
Who exactly is she?
What led to her death?
Are you the only one who knows of this.
or does Gu-cheon know as well?
I'm the only one who knows.
Do not tell him anything.
To capture the pond spirit.
I need to know who she was in life.
I will say this one last time.
Do not try to learn about the pond spirit.
You can catch it
without knowing its identity.
Do not look further into it.
Anyone who pries into shameful secrets
of the palace will die.
Even
a child of the royal bloodline.
Are you still unwell?
You are healing more slowly
than last time.
Sending 13 spirits back to the afterlife
drained my Yang energy.
I will never do this again.
Very well. So tell me now.
Why did you strangle me?
I did?
Yes. You looked
just like a spirit.
In the Realm of Gwi…
I lose Yang energy
every time I fight spirits.
Sometimes. I lose too much Yang energy
and become like a spirit
even out of the water.
It means I sometimes lose control
and do not know what I might do.
That is why I want to leave
the palace at once.
And that is the reason
I hate hunting spirits.
Well…
now that I have told you my secret.
you should
tell me what is on your mind.
Who is it that you want to kill
in the palace?
The one who killed my mother.
A cursed object containing human remains
was found in the salt storehouse.
Since you bore only a princess.
His Majesty has not set foot
in your chambers.
And out of jealousy. you cursed the Queen
and the other concubines. did you?
That is not true.
That cursed object was not my doing.
Enough.
This is your doing.
Continue.
-Your Majesty!
It was ten years ago.
Her Majesty the Queen Dowager
framed my mother and drove her out.
Father. please help.
Please stop Her Majesty the Queen Dowager.
Mother and the court ladies are innocent.
-It was because I heard strange things--
-Enough.
I will strip your mother of her title
and cast her out
for burying the cursed object.
That is her only way to survive.
But that cursed object
does not belong to Mother.
The spirits in the salt storehouse said.
"The serpent's cast skin killed--"
Hold your tongue.
Do not say
that my own child hears such things.
Unless you mean to disgrace
the royal house.
Do not tell anyone. Anyone at all.
Ever.
How foolish.
Utterly foolish.
You must always mind your words
in the palace.
Follow your mother and leave the palace!
Father.
How could you…
After we were cast out of the palace.
Mother was poisoned to death…
because she found the cursed object
and came close
to the secret of the pond spirit.
Someone killed my mother
to protect the secret of the pond spirit.
-Are you sure you should tell me this?
-I cannot unravel this secret without you.
I have no choice but to trust you.
Good grief.
What a life.
You should leave now.
We must uncover who the Most Favored Lady
of the Court really is. Get ready.
I went to the Queen Dowager's residence
to pay my respects.
and I saw Saeng-gang there.
She was dressed as a court lady
and with a strange man.
Did you give her
something dangerous to do?
You need not concern yourself with it.
Mother.
you need only concern yourself
with my son.
More importantly…
the Queen Dowager
is harboring ulterior motives.
It seems she intends
to make the eldest son of Prince Iksang
Crown Prince.
In any case.
we must act for the good
of the royal house and the nation.
You know what I had to endure to get here.
and yet you say such a thing to me?
Things will never go
as the Queen Dowager intends.
My son will inherit the throne.
Actually. I will make certain of it.
Yes.
Even if it means using spirits.
Why did we sneak into the chambers
of Lady Jang? We are not thieves.
Are you some kind of saint?
Lady Jang has spent her whole life
beside the Queen Dowager
and must know all her secrets.
So I mean to scare her into spilling
everything about the pond spirit.
Then do it properly.
What on earth are we doing?
Ma'am.
You are back earlier than usual.
I am not feeling well.
-I need rest.
-There!
This is bad.
Wait!
Who… who are you?
Who are you to enter without permission…
The pond spirit…
-The pond spirit is here.
-Wait. are you not that feng shui master?
-What are you doing here?
-Quiet!
-Look at these footprints on the floor.
-What…
Is this pond mud?
Leave at once!
-Or I will summon the guards.
-Wait. I can feel it.
The pond spirit…
What…
It is the pond spirit…
-Hey. You should earn your keep.
-You wretch!
Do what you are good at. Now.
-How dare you come in here!
-Hey. Hurry!
What do you think you are doing?
How dare you pull something so absurd!
Is anyone out there?
Where is that crying coming from…
I will wipe out every last seed
of the East Palace!
The pond spirit. It is here.
I told you
at the Queen Dowager's residence.
Won-gwi finds the one responsible
for its death…
Namo Amitabha.
You said you were a feng shui master.
Do you also know how to deal with spirits?
Speaking of which…
that damned spirit
will come for you again.
Again?
Then what should I do?
To keep the pond spirit away from here.
I need to know who it was in life.
Do not worry.
You can tell him everything you know.
He will keep it
from Her Majesty the Queen Dowager.
-He knows how to keep a secret.
-What?
Of course.
So.
who is the pond spirit?
The pond spirit is…
the last Most favored Lady of the Court
to the late King.
A woman of the lowest birth.
a mere maidservant.
caught the eye of the late King.
She received favor of His Majesty
and even conceived.
But it turned out
that she was romantically involved
with a royal guard.
When Her Majesty the Queen Dowager
learned of this.
she had the royal guard tortured.
Hold still!
But he did not confess easily.
Troops were dispatched.
and they found evidence.
-He eventually admitted his guilt.
-Go and search!
The Most Favored Lady of the Court
bore the child of the royal guard.
not of the late King.
After enduring torture.
she miscarried
and died holding a grudge
against the royal family.
I will wipe out every last seed
of the East Palace!
Then what happened to her body?
It was secretly taken out of the palace.
A grave would never have been an option.
What about her belongings?
They belonged to a traitor.
so they were all burned.
So there is nothing left of her?
I expect so. She had no family.
She died by her own wrongdoing
yet cursed the royal house?
There must be some greater reason.
involving the shameful secrets
of the palace.
I will have to ask the pond spirit myself.
Is there a way to summon it?
And what are you going to do?
There is no way to send it
to the afterlife.
Lady Jang said
everyone who entered the house
of the royal guard met an untimely death.
-Perhaps its spirit has settled there.
-Exactly.
There must be a reason he lingers
in that house instead of passing on.
Since they were lovers. the court lady
may have left her belongings behind.
I must go to the house of the royal guard.
Have you lost your mind?
-Do you want to die an untimely death?
-We have no other choice.
I am the only one
who can leave the palace.
There is a way.
I can become a soul and leave.
Is that even possible?
Yes. but it is dangerous.
If the soul drifts too far from the body…
it will be hard for it to return.
If things go wrong.
the soul may be lost…
and become a spirit.
If that happens.
I will surely become an ak-gwi.
Ak-gwi?
When those with heavy karma die.
they become an ak-gwi.
In life…
Are you all right?
Do you see something
in the well?
You do not look well.
If you need my Yang energy--
Then you would have to hold me close
and share your warmth.
Can you do that for me?
Never mind.
I have no intention of doing that either.
Then will you remain this way?
No. it will get worse.
Then from now on. I will accompany you
to the Realm of Gwi.
Two are better than one.
Teach me how.
Are you asking me
to teach you how to die?
I should find a way to help you.
There is only one way.
Go and tell the King
that there is no way
to catch the pond spirit now
and that I may lose control
and start killing people.
so he must release me from the palace.
I cannot do that.
You have to find a way.
Let go of the naive thought
that His Majesty will release you.
Then I will leave this palace in death.
If I die here.
I will turn into a relentless ak-gwi.
And when I do…
I will come for the King first.
How dare you
threaten to kill His Majesty.
What does it matter to you?
You hate the King as well.
I do.
Yet he is the King of this nation.
All royals are the same.
They use whoever they please
and do not even care
if people live or die.
You are no different.
Miss.
Royal Noble Consort Sukbin Choi
wishes to see you.
It has been a while. Grandmother.
His Majesty told me everything.
How could you think of disguising yourself
as a court lady to enter the palace?
And what brings you to the palace.
Grandmother?
You hated coming to the palace
more than anyone.
Will you not answer my question?
Same as always. You change the subject.
I am exhausted.
Oh dear.
Saeng-gang.
I hope you do not get caught up
in palace strife again.
as you did as a child.
You are the only one
who worries about me. Grandmother.
After Mother and I were driven
out of the palace.
there was no one but you
who took care of us.
What is that man like?
I have heard he is strange and dangerous.
He may be strange.
but he is the one I need most right now.
And he may be dangerous…
but I do not mind.
as we will not be friends.
The palace is a place
where the sane become ill.
and those with darkness in their hearts
become evil.
So you must be careful.
Gu-cheon.
You have missed me. have you not?
Come here.
This is strange.
People died here before.
That is why the well was sealed.
And another maidservant died?
Earlier at dawn. a maidservant saw a man
near the well while carrying wash water.
-Is that so?
-Yes.
It was the feng shui master
staying at the East Palace.
Shall I send him to the State Tribunal?
No. The 70th birthday
of the Queen Dowager is near.
This must be handled discreetly.
We must not cause a disturbance.
-Yes. ma'am.
Gu-cheon.
What is this bloodstain?
What is this?
What are you doing out at night?
Whose blood is this?
What do you mean "whose blood"?
Are you saying I harmed someone?
Then is it your blood?
Where were you hurt? And why?
Perhaps I had a nosebleed in my sleep.
After fighting the court ladies' spirits.
I barely had any strength left.
Even that damned Ggeomeoksali
kept draining my Yang energy.
I already told you
that every time I enter the Realm of Gwi.
I lose my Yang energy.
Prince Yeongan.
You need to get your strength back.
It was not this severe before.
but his condition suddenly worsened.
Coming back to the East Palace
reminds me of my childhood here.
This place still gives me chills.
What brings you here.
to a place you find so chilling?
How much longer do I have to wait?
I came to hear your answer myself.
First. please let me leave the palace.
If I stay here any longer.
the Yin energy of this place will kill me.
If you let me leave.
I will capture the pond spirit
no matter what.
Tomorrow is the 70th birthday banquet
of the Queen Dowager.
Eliminate the pond spirit
and bring Prince Yeongan back to health.
You have until noon tomorrow.
-Your Majesty.
-Your life is no concern of mine.
You will not leave this palace
until I die.
If my son cannot walk into the banquet
on his own two feet tomorrow.
I will kill you
and bind your soul to the palace forever.
Do you understand?
Wait. are you not the feng shui master
staying in the East Palace?
Why are you here?
This place is for women only.
-Where is she?
-What?
I may be young. but I am a court lady.
Watch how you speak to me.
This will not do.
-You must help me.
-What? That man dares…
Miss Saeng-gang gave the order. Follow me.
What is he doing?
What on earth are you doing?
What exactly did Miss Saeng-gang
order you to do?
Place this brass basin
near the house of the royal guard
in Jungchon.
Mark my words.
You must never spill this water.
I have no choice but to use my blood…
become a soul.
and seek out the royal guard.
What is going on?
It seems the lightning
struck the jujube tree.
An ill omen.
It is the 70th birthday of Her Majesty.
What a calamity.
Good heavens.
Ever heard of
lightning-struck jujube wood?
No. I have not.
More importantly. every peach tree
in the palace will be gone at this rate.
That is why I asked.
This wood rots when it strikes a spirit.
so it is utterly useless.
Is lightning-struck jujube wood
any different?
A jujube tree struck by lightning
is sturdy and dense enough
to sink as I do.
It drives away evil spirits.
Perfect for striking them down.
Heaven is on our side.
This man…
This is exhausting.
You…
You cannot…
You cannot take it.
Stop it!
What are you trying to protect.
even in death?
The fault is mine.
I must return it.
I killed her!
Your blood is on this sword.
Take it.
I killed her.
After she became a woman of the King.
I framed her
and betrayed her.
In return for doing so.
for making a false confession.
the Queen Dowager promised
to spare my family from annihilation.
She had made
the baby's first shirt with all her heart…
and I buried it beneath this tree.
I must
protect it
until she returns.
I must beg
her forgiveness.
What are you trying to do?
Wait! Miss Saeng-gang!
Gu-cheon!
Is he alive?
This madman entered the Realm of Gwi
without the rope.
I cannot even pull his soul back.
Look.
Where are you now?
Look. Gu-cheon!
Are you even on your way back?
If the soul drifts too far from the body.
it will be hard for it to return.
-Wake up. Gu-cheon!
-The soul may be lost and become a spirit.
If that happens.
I will surely become an ak-gwi.
I will not let you wander alone
as a spirit.
I will come to you.
Please wait for me.
Please.
Gu-cheon.
Come here.
Mother.
Gu-cheon!
Do not go any closer!
-Gu-cheon.
-Let us leave this place.
That gwi-mae lures people to their deaths.
-You missed me. did you not?
-Gu-cheon!
-Please look properly!
-Come here.
Mother.
Gu-cheon!
I died because of you.
Let go of me.
Gu-cheon!
Then I will leave this palace in death.
If I die here.
I will turn into a relentless ak-gwi.
And when I do…
I will come for the King first.
Could he be…
Subtitle translation by: Yun-hee Jang